Guide to the The Ewing Family Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Presley K. Ewing
  - Correspondence
    - Politics
      - Local
        - To Mayor and City Council of Houston re: Public Light, May 11, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 305)
      - Highway Issue
        - To Houston Chronicle, November 24, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 306)
        - To M. E. Foster, November 24, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 307)
        - To Governor Miriam A. Ferguson, November 24, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 308)
        - From M. E. Foster, November 25, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 309)
        - To M. E. Foster, November 27, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 310)
        - From James E. Ferguson, November 28, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 311)
        - To James E. Ferguson, November 30, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 312)
        - From Max W. Hart, November 30, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 313)
        - To Max W. Hart, December 1, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 314)
        - From James E. Ferguson, January 28, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 315)
      - Lindsey Blayney
        - re: Resignation, September 22, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 316)
        - To Dr. Edgar Odell Lovett, September 26, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 317)
        - From Dr. Edgar Odell Lovett, September 28, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 318)
        - To Dr. Edgar Odell Lovett, September 29, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 319)
      - “Taxation”
        - “Important Bulletin Regarding Proposed Taxation Legislation”, January 29, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 320)
        - From Roy G. Watson, February 1, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 321)
        - From C. B. Gillespie, February 2, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 322)
        - From Charles Murphy, February 8, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 323)
        - From W.L. Marbury, February 17, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 324)
        - From Wm. H. Clark, July 7, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 325)
    - Postcards
      - From Leila Werlein re: Christmas, undated (Box 2, Folder 326)
      - From Leila Werlein re: Birthday, July 21, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 327)
      - From Leila Werlein, December 20, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 328)
      - From Leila Werlein re: General, April 16, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 329)
      - To Miss J.H. Whitney re: Trip, June 18, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 330)
      - From L re: Trip, September 19, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 331)
    - Professional Organizations and Charities
      - From Ben F. Wilson re: Meeting of Texas Bar Association, May 28, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 332)
      - To Mr. J.S. Pyeatt re: Relief of German Children, January 8, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 333)
      - From R.W. Franklin, Esq. re: Luncheon at Houston Club, April 1, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 334)
      - To R.W. Franklin, Esq. re: Luncheon at Houston Club, April 3, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 335)
      - To Committee Tubercular Hospital Fund re: Donation, October 7, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 336)
    - Recommendation Letters
      - Appointment to U.S. Supreme Court
        - From F. A. Williams, July 15, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 337)
        - From Chief Justice T.J. Brown, July 22, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 338)
        - From Garret J. Garretson, July 24, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 339)
        - From W.R. Blakemore, July 27, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 340)
      - Bessie V. Sullivan
        - re: Recommendation Letter, December 13, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 341)
        - re: Recommendation Letter to Department of State, December 17, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 342)
        - re: Recommendation Letter to Daniel E. Garrett, January 21, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 343)
      - Sybil Turville
        - To Miss Sybil Turville re: Recommendation Letters, May 16, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 344)
        - From Morris Sheppard re: Recommendation of Sybil Turville, May 21, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 345)
        - To Morris Sheppard re: Sybil Turville, May 26, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 346)
      - Various
        - To Murray B. Jones re: Joseph W. Bailey for Governor, August 5, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 347)
        - To Governor Miriam A. Ferguson re: Appointment of J.D. Harvey to Commission of Appeals, June 20, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 348)
  - Speeches
    - “Address of Welcome Delivered Before Trans Mississippi Commercial Congress”, April 17, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 349)
    - Delivered at Banquet to Judge John G. Tod, undated (Box 2, Folder 350)
    - “In the Union of Brotherhood There is Strength”, undated (Box 2, Folder 351)
    - “The De-Facto Wife”, undated (Box 2, Folder 352)
    - Transcript of Unknown Speech re: Agriculture and Politics, undated (Box 2, Folder 353)
    - “Echoes of Lawyer’s Banquet”, undated (Box 2, Folder 354)
  - Various Materials
    - Articles
      - “Klan Oath Revealed”, undated (Box 2, Folder 355)
      - “People’s Forum For Fair Play” by Quincy Ewing, November 29, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 356)
      - “Supreme Bench Vacancy,” by W.P. Hobby, undated (Box 2, Folder 357)
      - “The Post’s Poultry Department”, September 14, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 358)
      - “Torn Out Like a Page from Houston’s Past…”, February 25, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 359)
    - Financial
      - Check Stub to Embry & Gillette, April 6, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 360)
      - Check Stub to Ewing Veatch, March 18, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 361)
      - Check Stub to J.H. Whitney, February 21, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 362)
      - Invoice Brock’s Doelen Hotel, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 363)
      - Invoice Cosmo Hotel, June-July 1924 (Box 2, Folder 364)
      - Invoice Grand Hotel Savoia-Majestic, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 365)
      - Invoice Hotel Matignon, undated (Box 2, Folder 366)
      - Invoice Palace Hotel Lucerne, July 1924 (Box 2, Folder 367)
      - Invoice Westheimer Warehouse Co. Inc, April 28, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 368)
      - Receipt for Donation The George Washington Masonic National Memorial Association, January 16, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 369)
      - Receipt for Dr. John H. Wood, August 1, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 370)
      - Statement of Disbursements, undated (Box 2, Folder 371)
      - Subscriber’s Receipt The American Legion Endowment Fund, undated (Box 2, Folder 372)
    - Itinerary
      - Itinerary of Tour for Judge and Mrs. Presley K. Ewing, undated (Box 2, Folder 373)
      - Judge Ewing’s Amended Itinerary, undated (Box 2, Folder 374)
    - Inventories
      - Gladys’ Silver Inventory, undated (Box 2, Folder 375)
      - Household Item Inventory, undated (Box 2, Folder 376)
      - Silver Utensil Inventory, undated (Box 2, Folder 377)
    - List of Friends
      - Mr. Ewing’s Personal List Announcements, June 12, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 378)
      - Mr. Ewing’s Personal List Christmas Cards, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 379)
      - X-mas Card List, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 380)
    - Various
      - Business Card “Presley K. Ewing”, undated (Box 2, Folder 381)
      - Comments to the Court of Civil Appeals at Galveston re: Death of Presley K. Ewing, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 382)
      - Debutante and Guest List, undated (Box 2, Folder 383)
      - Obituaries for Presley K. Ewing, February 1927 (Box 2, Folder 384)
      - Pamphlet “Argument in Favor of the Passage of the Pending Amnesty Bill”, undated (Box 2, Folder 385)
      - Pamphlet for St. John’s Cemetery Association By Laws, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 386)
      - Poem, undated (Box 2, Folder 387)
      - Receipt for Duty and Identification Coupon, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 388)
      - The National Committee of the Woodrow Wilson Foundation Certificate, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 389)
- Josie Vesta Ewing
  This series contains documents revolving primarily around the travels of Josie Vesta Ewing. Included are journals, correspondence and articles written by Vesta during her travels through Europe. Also included are poems penned by Vesta in both French and English.
  - Articles
    - Vesta Ewing Veatch Obituaries, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Kittredge Vinson Birthday, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - “Prize Winners at Baby Show”, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - “Houstonian is Made Naples Vice-Consul”, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - “J. Kittredge Vinson is Vice-Consul at Naples”, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - re: Vesta Ewing’s Return to Houston, June 5, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Houston Chronicle re: Daughters of the American Revolution, March 13, 194- (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence
    - Birth of Vesta (Daughter)
      - From Mary Renick, October 30, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - From Gladys (Ewing) Combes, October 31, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - From Gladys (Ewing) Combes, November 1, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - From Nelle Cross Caldwell, November 2, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - From Lillian Tirrell, November 3, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - From Jack Cassidy, November 11, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - From Eleanor Kirby/Florist Cards, November 12, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - From Enid Cary, November 16, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - From Lillian, November 17, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - From Antoinette Smith, November 17, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - From Mary Ewing, November 18, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - From Maurice Long, November 20, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - From Leila Werlein, November 20, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - From Edith, November 29, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - From Aunt Daisy, December 11, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Trip to Europe
      - re: Gibraltar, June 8, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - re: Fourth of July, July 5, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - re: Rome/Pompeii, July 12, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - re: Rome, July 13, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - re: Rome, July 1902 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - re: Naples, July 17, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - re: Florence, July 21, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - re: Venice, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - re: Holland, July 23, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - re: Switzerland, July 23, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - re: The Rhine, July 29, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - re: The Hague, August 1, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - re: Paris, August 8, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - re: London, August 9, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - re: London/Trip home, August 9, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - re: London, August 12, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Various
      - From Gladys re: General, October 13, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Christmas Card From Gladys, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - From Mr. Sgt. & Mrs. Maurice Long re: Birthday Card, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - From Unknown Author, October 3, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - From Vesta (Daughter) re: Grindelwald, January 14, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Letter to Santa Claus, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Poetry
    - “A Man of Yesterday”, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - “Call Me Not Lonely”, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - “The Easiest Way”, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - “George Washington”, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - “The Green Book”, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - “Le Crepuscule”/”Separation”/”Somebody Cares”, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - “The Other Son”, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - “Peter”, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - “The Red Roofs”, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - “To My Father, Presley K. Ewing”, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - “To You, My Beloved”, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - “The Twilight Hour”, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - “Warning,” by Virginia Leddy (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - “The Vigil”, April 17, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - “My Three", May 2, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - “Parting”, May 18, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - “Friends”, June 4, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - “Wiedersehen”, July 6, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - “O Gentle Death”, January 16, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - “Giving”, November 26, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - “Lord, Pity Them”, December 25, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - “To Mrs. Julia Huston”, February 5, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Book of Poetry, undated (Ovs box 6, Item 1)
    - Rhymes: Good, Bad, and Indifferent, July 1904 (Ovs box 6, Item 2)
  - Scrapbooks and Journals
    - School
      - Classmates, May 21, 1902 (Ovs box 6, Item 3)
      - Pleasant Incidents of the Session Spent at Mrs. Finch’s School, 1902-1903 (Ovs box 6, Item 4)
      - Books I Have Read, 1903 (Ovs box 6, Item 5)
    - Trips
      - Diary During Trip to Europe, 1902 (Ovs box 6, Item 6)
      - Journal-Trip to Europe, 1929 (Ovs box 6, Item 7)
      - Scrapbook of Articles Written About Trip to Europe, 1930 (Ovs box 6, Item 8)
      - Passport, 1937 (Ovs box 6, Item 9)
      - “My Trip Abroad-Vol. I”, September 17, 1937 - March 26, 1938 (Ovs box 6, Item 10)
      - “My Trip Abroad-Vol. II”, March 26, 1938 (Ovs box 6, Item 11)
      - Passport, 1947 (Ovs box 6, Item 12)
      - Journal-Trip to Europe, 1947 (Ovs box 6, Item 13)
      - Journal-Trip to Europe, 1947 (Ovs box 6, Item 14)
      - Journal-Trip to Europe, 1947 (Ovs box 6, Item 15)
      - Journal-Trip to Italy, undated (Ovs box 6, Item 16)
    - Various
      - Scrapbook, undated (Ovs box 6, Item 17)
    - Wedding
      - The Bride’s Book, 1908 (Ovs box 6, Item 18)
      - Cupid’s Proverbs: A Wedding Book, 1908 (Ovs box 6, Item 19)
      - “The Form of Solemnization of Matrimony”, 1908 (Ovs box 6, Item 20)
      - Guest Book, 1908 (Ovs box 6, Item 21)
      - Wedding Bells, 1908 (Ovs box 6, Item 22)
  - Various Materials
    - Cabaret Du Ciel Illusions et Visions Artistiques, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Further History of the Ewing Family, October 7, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Pamphlet: The Church of Saint Ursula, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Program: Concert for the Benefit of the Seaman’s Fund, July 8, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Houston Mothers Congress Baby, November 1912 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Reunion Class of ’02, June 14, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 72)